The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
♪ Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano ♪
The dreams I see are my secret
♪ Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano ♪
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
♪ Akai manto hira hira ♪
A red cape fluttering
♪ Uma o tobasu oujo ♪
Galloping on a horse—the princess
♪ Sore ga atashi ♪
That’s me!
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Lula-dula-lula-dula ♪
-
♪ Lulu laa, lulaa ♪
♪ Ribon no kishi wa ♪
The Knight of the Ribbon,
♪ Honto wa hontto wa ♪
Truly, truly,
♪ Atashi nano sa ♪
It’s really me!
Thirty-Second Episode
The Silver Ship
Sapphire's Treasure
Silverland...
Silver as in the metal.
Silverland means the Land of Silver.
True to its name,
silver was once endlessly mined here.
But,
because of it, ugly conflicts arose.
The king used brute force, even starting a war to hoard all the silver.
The realm fell into chaos and the people suffered, until a hero rose up in outrage.
The hero took all the silver, built a silver ship, and sank it in a swamp.
That secret is recorded here.
Time passed,
and the old legend was eventually forgotten.
So that's how it is...
Standing there reading for days on end... Geez.
So, is there anything good in those?
Who hit me on the head?!
It's so damn long, I genuinely mistook it for something else!
What was that for?!
Serves you right!
Old man! It's the master's report!
Take this!
Take that, you fool!
Hey, let's take a quick break.
A break won't hurt, right?
What's this?
"Beneath three half-moons, a silver marsh slumbers in peace."
"As ripples spread, the Silver Ship rises,"
"and the Silver Knight cries out to the moon:"
"O Moon, O Moon, aid me and grant me power!"
This must be a clue showing the location of the Silver Ship!
What?
The legendary Silver Ship?
You mean that silver ship nobody can find?
That's right.
This text must point to where the Silver Ship is hidden.
So where exactly is that place?
Well...
I don't understand it at all, but...
Whatever it takes, use those clues to find that silver ship!
...And that's how it went.
Hmm. Is the Silver Ship really that great of a treasure?
It really is.
If it falls into the wrong hands, we'll be in big trouble.
I'm a little worried since Duralumin knows about this, too.
Sapphire!
I have a great idea!
A great idea?
Listen, it's a really good one.
Sapphire, you and I will find the treasure
and share it with everyone in the kingdom!
That's great!
If we share it, everyone in the country will be rich, and
Duralumin won't be able to use it for evil!
That really is a great idea!
Treasure hunt time!
Search for the Silver Ship!
Ah, crescent moon, crescent moon... silver ship, silver ship... ah, crescent moon...
Did you figure something out, Your Grace?
Ah, I want to get my hands on it no matter what.
Man, it really is an amazing treasure, Nylon.
What do you mean?
Of course we want to get our hands on it!
We'll get that amazing treasure, sell it off abroad, and hire an army.
An insanely powerful army!
And then...
Got a bite!
I caught one! I caught one!
Oh my...
Sakana-san, have you seen a ship made of silver
at the bottom of this pond?
A huge silver ship.
You don't know? Ah, thank you anyway.
Don't go getting caught again!
You let my dinner get away!
Hey, Mizutori-san.
Is there a silver ship sunken in this water?
Three half-moons... Three half-moons.
A silver ship, a silver spring...
Three half-moons...
Don't be ridiculous! I mean moons!
How could there be three of them?!
Have you solved the riddle?
Curse that Nylon! I told him to solve the riddle, what is he doing?!
All right!
Oh, Great Duke Duralumin!
What do you mean, "All right"?!
Don't tell me you were playing around instead of solving the riddle?
Great Duke Duralumin, you must be joking.
What about the riddle of the Silver Ship?
Well, I'm almost there.
What do you mean, "almost", Nylon?
Well, as for the half-moons...
This is it!
I've got it!
The half-moons mean archery bows!
Three bows lined up—that means three half-moons!
Look at that target over there!
Those three half-moons must refer to Bow Mountain
deep in the Northern Forest.
That's where the Silver Ship is sunken!
Three bows.
It really is three half-moons.
No way!
There's no swamp!
Damn it!
So much for the Silver Swamp!
Water!
Why was the grass moving?
No, wait.
Maybe this area used to be a swamp.
I knew it!
There used to be water here.
Then what on earth was I riding all this time...?
It's silver!
Found you!
I've finally found it!
The Silver Ship is right down here!
This has to be part of it!
That's it!
This is...the mast!
That's it! Greenery!
I found the Silver Ship!
Tsukiyo, kotaete kure.
- Moon, answer me.
Watashi wa nannen nemutte ita no da?
- How many years have I slept?
Dare ga watashi o okoshita no da?
- Who awakened me?
Tsukiyo, oshiete kure.
- Moon, tell me.
Mata wazawai ga chikazuite iru no ka?
- Is calamity approaching again?
Naraba, ware ni chikara o ataeyo.
- Then grant me power!
Hey, old Fukuro-san!
It's a very old story, but have you ever heard of a silver ship
sunk in a pond around here?
I see.
Thank you very much.
Goodbye, Tink.
Don't be discouraged, Sapphire.
Let's look again tomorrow.
- Goodbye!
Three half-moons in a row!
That's Bow Mountain!
Opal, stop!
So that's what the three half-moons meant!
Hurry, Opal!
It's Bow Mountain!
No matter how much we search, there's no swamp.
According to the text, the Silver Swamp should be around here, though.
What's that?
Omae wa dare da.
- Who are you?
Nani shi ni kita.
- Why are you here?
I am Prince Sapphire of this land.
I came looking for the legendary swamp.
Yahari omae ga watashi o okoshita no da na.
- So it was you who woke me.
Yokubari no oji me.
- You greedy prince!
Hakugin no numa ni wa ippo mo chikazukasenu zo.
- I won't let you get a single step closer to the Silver Swamp!
So the Silver Swamp really is here!
Onore yokubari ningen me!
- Curse you, greedy human!
What are you doing?
It's all over.
Mun-ku Tsuki yo... tsuki yo... watashi o tasukero...
- O Moon, O Moon, O moon, help me!
Watashi ni chikara o ataeyo ka...
- Will you give me strength.
Now!
Tsuki yo...
- O Moon!
What on earth happened?
It vanished!
No way!
Vampire bats!
I have to escape before this fire goes out...
A door!
It's hot!
Damn it!
They're getting closer!
We have to get inside!
I made it!
Hurry!
Move it!
Dawdle any longer and dawn will break!
Come on, hurry to Bow Mountain!
Nylon!
Did it really weigh 100 tons?
Absolutely. Judging by that mast, 100 tons is an understatement.
It's enough to break this crane.
I see!
Incredible!
Look how huge it is!
Even the sails are made of silver!
With this much, we could share it with everyone in the world!
Nani sawaru denai ka!
- Do not touch that!
That voice... It's him!
Kono fune wa watasanu!
- I will not hand over this ship!
Omae ni wa ano yokubari no ou no oroka na chi ga nagarete iru!
- The foolish blood of that greedy king flows in your veins!
Who on earth are you?!
Watashi wa suuhyakunen kono fune o mamotte kita gin no sei da!
- I am the Silver Spirit, guardian of this ship for centuries!
The mountain of treasure is just ahead, sir!
Hurry!
We're close!
Please listen to me!
I want to share this with everyone in the kingdom... no, the whole world!
Damare!
- Silence!
Omae no sosen no oroka na ou mo,
- Your foolish ancestor said the same thing,
sonna koto o itte gin o hitorijime ni shiyou to shita no da!
- trying to keep all the silver for himself!
Sono tame ni,
- Because of that,
heiwa datta Silverland wa midare,
- peaceful Silverland was thrown into turmoil—
sensou ga okori, nansen no ie ga yakare,
- war broke out, burning thousands of homes and
nansen no hito no inochi ga ubawareta ka...
- claiming thousands of lives...
Omae no kotoba nado ni damasare wa shinai!
- I won't be fooled by your words!
I'm not tricking you!
I don't want silver, gold, or jewels!
I just want to share it with the poor!
Please believe me!
I'll do anything for that!
Damare!
- Silence!
Hear me, Silver Spirit!
I don't want silver, gold, or jewels!
I just want to give them to the poor!
Silver Spirit!
Are you listening?
Where did you go?
Your body...
Watashi no karada wa gin ni yotte
- Only my soul,
heiwa o midasaremai to suru tamashii dake
- which refuses to let silver disrupt the peace,
ga yoroi ni noriutsutte iru no!
- has possessed this armor!
Look out!
Omae ga watashi o tasuketa?
- Did you save me?
Naze da?
- Why?
What...?
Silver Spirit!
Oji...
- Prince...
You've awakened?
Tanomi ga aru,
- I have a favor to ask!
Are o miyo
- Look at that!
That's...
So da!
- So it is!
Kono gin no fune o onore no mono ni shiyo
- Fools consumed by greed
to yoku ni tsukareta orokamono ga yattekita no da
- have come to claim this silver ship!
Lower the crane!
Watashi wa tsuki no hikari o abinai to hatarakenai no da
- I can't move without bathing in moonlight!
Watashi no kawari ni kono yoroi o kite, gin no fune o mamotte kure.
- Wear this armor in my place and protect the silver ship!
Kono yoroi wa kitto, sonata o mamoru daro.
- This armor will surely protect you!
Understood.
A fish... No, we hooked the ship!
That's it! Raise the crane!
Raise the crane!
Raise it faster!
Here it comes!
It's coming up!
It's the silver ship!
Come on, don't dawdle!
Pull it up quickly!
What is that?
So you are the fools blinded by greed!
Who on earth... are you?!
I am the Silver Spirit, guardian of this swamp!
I won't let greedy fools have this ship!
Bows!
Shoot that monster with your bows!
It's useless!
It's no use!
Spears are no match for me!
It's a monster!
Wait!
I had no idea a monster like that existed!
Hide behind that furnace!
Nylon, take a look!
It's coming!
Well, Nylon?
Right now, it's fighting the soldiers...
I've got it!
Release the chocks on this cart!
We'll run it down!
We did it!
The water is coming out!
Help!
Save me!
What a nightmare!
How dare you climb up before me!
It's your fault we missed out on the treasure!
Shut up!
I go first!
Oji yo, omae no okage de gin no fune o mamoru koto ga dekita.
- Prince, thanks to you, the Silver Ship was saved.
Kono fune o omae ni oguro.
- I give this ship to you.
What?
Gin no fune wa omae no takara da.
- The Silver Ship is your treasure.
Tadashi, omae ga oi o tsugi,
- However, I will keep it at the bottom of the marsh
heiwa na kuni o tsukuru made
- until you take the throne
watashi ga numa no soko de azakatte oko.
- and build a peaceful kingdom.
Sore made watashi wa zutto kono
- Until then, I will watch over you
hakugin no numa no naka kara mimamotte iyo.
- from within this Silver Marsh.
Please watch over me.
Sapphire will build a peaceful kingdom.
Sore made watashi wa zutto kono
- Until then, I will watch over you
numa-numa kara mimamotte iyo.
- from deep within this marsh.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen ♪
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
♪ Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen ♪
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
♪ Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo ♪
Even if demons come, even if storms arrive,
♪ tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai ♪
Our bonded hearts will never part.
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
♪ Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa ♪
-
♪ Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo! ♪
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP